Guide to the Clayton Family Papers
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Dorothea Clayton estate papers, Series II
  - Probate documents
    - Legacy receipts. Stamps and Taxes, Form 1
      - Elizabeth Townshend, Elizabeth Ellen Feilden, Margaretta Dorothea Townshend: furniture, 1849 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Ralph Walters: £4876.15.3, 1849 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Dorothea June Walters: £1000, 1849 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - William Dixon: £50, 1849 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - William Farres: £50, 1849 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Oliver Farres: £50, 1849 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Residuary account. Inland Revenue. Form 3. Draft copy? of an account of Dorothea Clayton 's assets at the time of her death., 1849 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Residuary account. Stamps and taxes. Form 3. Account of Dorothea Clayton 's assets at the time of her death, with tax assessment and receipt., 1849 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Regulations to be observed for obtaining a return of duty on probates of wills. [London: ca. 1849]. 1 v. Caption title., [Circa 1849]; Great Britain. Laws, statutes, etc., 1837-1901 (Victoria) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Draft of sworn statement petitioning court for the return of a portion of the duties paid on Dorothea Clayton's estate., 1850 January 7; Clayton, William (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Sworn statements declaring that on February 13, 1850 Dorothea Clayton borrowed £40,000 from William, and promised to pay him that amount after her death., 1850 January 25; Clayton, William; Payne, Lydia (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Legacy documents
    - Letter to Lydia Payne, regarding removal of inherited furniture and other items from the house, on behalf of Mrs. Townshend and Misses Feilden, 1849 September 27; Townshend, John (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Enclosed: Letter authorizing an agent to receive items from the house on their behalf., 1849 September 28; Townshend, Priscilla; Feilden, Elizabeth Ellen (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Valuation of articles bequeathed to Priscilla Townshend and Misses Feilden, including several pieces of furniture, paintings and etchings, 1849 September 28; Gillow & Co (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - List of legacies and recipients, [Circa 1849 Oct 1]; Clayton, William (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Receipts for legacies given to servants
      - A[…?] Gayforth ?: £10, 1849 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Elizabeth Barnes: £10, 1849 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Richard Benjamin: £10, 1849 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Account of payments to Lydia Payne, including a legacy inherited from Dorothea Clayton, a gift from Walter Clayton Clayton, and a payment for completing an affidavit [See Folder 11: "Sworn statements by William Clayton Clayton and Lydia Payne," 1850 Jan 25]. Signed by Lydia Payne., 1850 February 25; Clayton, William (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Copy of Account of payments to Lydia Payne, 1850 February 25; Clayton, William (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Estate bills and receipts
    - Funeral expenses including coffin, plaques, burial clothes, mourning clothes, undertaker, attendants, hearse and cemetery fees., 1849 September; Gillow & Co (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Summary of fees for funeral and inventory of the house, 1849 [October]; Gillow & Co (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Probate expenses, summary, 1849 October 2; Bowdler & Bathwist (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Probate expenses, itemized, 1849 October [2]; Bowdler & Bathwist (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Unpaid bills incurred by Dorothea Clayton before her death, including repairs to pillows and window sash; inventory and appraisal of house and stables; certificate of burial; miscellaneous house repairs., 1849 October 11; Gillow & Co (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Legal fees associated with burial, probate, sale of Dorothea Clayton 's assets, petitioning court for the return of a portion of the duties paid on Dorothea Clayton 's estate, Undated; Shaw & Newstead (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sale of stocks and other assets
    - Letter to William Clayton Clayton, regarding sale of a chair., 1849 October 15; Ward, John (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letter to William Clayton Clayton, regarding stock sale., 1849 October 17; Dixon, William (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letter to William Clayton Clayton, regarding power of attorney and stock sale., 1849 October 26; Dixon, William (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letter to William Clayton Clayton, regarding stock sale., 1849 November 1; Dixon, William (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letter to William Clayton Clayton, regarding power of attorney and stock sale., 1849 November 2; Dixon, William (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Receipt for stock sale., 1859 November 20; Langdale & Son (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Receipt for sale of Dorothea Clayton's stock, with, on second leaf: William Dixon. Letter (Wm. Dixon) to William Clayton Clayton, regarding stock sale., 1849 November 21; Langdale & Son (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Receipt for stock sale., with, on second leaf: Dixon Brooks Dixon. Letter to William Clayton Clayton, regarding sale of Dorothea Clayton 's stock., 1850 July 31; Langdale & Son (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Receipt for stock sale., 1850 August 20; Langdale & Son (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Receipt for stock sale., 1851 October 30; Langdale & Son (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Receipt for stock sale., 1852 January 21; Langdale & Son (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Annuities certificates
    - Three pounds ten shillings per cent reduced annuities. L1,000 interest., 1837 December 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - £3:5s. per cent annuities. £500 share., 1847 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - £3:5s. per cent annuities. £1000 share., 1847 December 16 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - £3:5s. per cent annuities. £800 share., 1848 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - £3:5s. per cent annuities. £700 share., 1848 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - £3:5s. per cent annuities. £500 share., 1849 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - £3:5s. per cent annuities. £800 share., 1849 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Estate of Ralph Clayton.
    - Legal agreement regarding estate of Ralph Clayton, between John Feilden, Dorothea Clayton, Sir Alan Chambre, John Delafield Phelps, Charles Bicknell and Ellen Clayton., 1814 June 13 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Note regarding estate of Ralph Clayton, written on the back of a letter., 1849 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Clayton Family papers
    - Bill for legal services related to Dorothea changing her name from Brack to Clayton., 1814 February; Bigland, Norroy & Register (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bill and receipt for William Clayton Walters ' dues., 1849 June 12; Lincoln's Inn (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - List of tasks after Dorothea Clayton 's death., 1849 November (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Fair copy of a legal memorandum regarding security for repayment of a loan made to William Clayton Clayton by John Clayton. Includes agreement by William Clayton Clayton to mortgage the house, stable and other properties to John Clayton., 1871 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous notes regarding assignment of turnpike tolls., [After 1800] (Box 1, Folder 17)